Rensselaer W. Lee Papers, 1930-1984 (bulk 1960-1980 ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
Rensselaer W. Lee Papers
1960-1980
1930-1984
C0552
Princeton University. Library. Dept. of Rare Books and Special Collections Manuscripts Division One Washington Road Princeton, New Jersey 08544 USA
18.0 linear feet 45 full sized archival boxes
Lee, Rensselaer W. (Rensselaer Wright), 1898-1984.
Consists of the papers of Princeton art historian Rensselaer W. Lee, including correspondence, lectures, and manuscripts and notes for two published works.
Rensselaer W. Lee graduated with honors from Princeton in 1920, and in 1926 he received a doctorate in English. He became professor of art history at Northwestern University from 1931 to 1940. Following World War II, he served on the American committee to conserve and restore European monuments and art damaged in the War. Rensselaer W. Lee was the Marquand Professor of art history at Princeton from 1954 to 1966, specializing in baroque and art theory. In 1958 he was part of a team that documented Byzantine art treasures at the sixth-century monastery of St. Catherine on Mount Sinai. He served as president of the American Academy in Rome from 1968-1971.
The collection consists of articles, lectures, correspondence, printed matter, photographs, and research material of Lee. Included are files of professional correspondence (1930-1984), papers of organizations to which he belonged, such as the American Academy in Rome (president, 1968-1971), outlines and lectures for his art history courses, and a great deal of notes, letters, and photographs of works of art relating to the pictorial illustration of the works of the Italian poets Lodovico Ariosto (1474-1533) and Torquato Tasso (1544-1595) and the relationship of Renaissance painting and poetry. Manuscripts and related material for two books, Names on Trees: Ariosto in Art (1977) and U Pictura Poesis: The Humanistic Theory of Painting (1967), and a lecture, "Poetry Into Painting: Tasso and Art" (1970), are also included.
Arranged roughly as follows: index cards, notebooks, professional correspondence, organizations, research notes and photographs, correspondence/recommendations, articles, and lectures.
Please consult with Rare Books and Special Collections about having the collection recalled to Firestone Library for your use. This process normally requires 48-72 hours notice.
The collection is open for research.
AM86-6. Compiled by L. Judge.
Publications by Lee: Names on Trees: Ariosto in Art (Princeton: Princeton University Press, 1977), Ut Pictura Poesis: The Humanistic theory of Painting (New York: W.W. Norton, 1967)
Ariosto, Lodovico, 1474-1533 -- Criticism and interpretation.; Tasso, Torquato, 1544-1595 -- Criticism and interpretation.; American Academy in Rome.; Art -- History.; Art -- Study and teaching -- New Jersey -- Princeton -- 20th century.; Art and literature -- Italy -- 16th century.; Art, Italian.; European literature -- Renaissance, 1440-1600.; Humanism in art.; Names carved on trees.; Painting, Modern -- Europe -- 17th-18th centuries.; Painting, Modern -- Italy -- 17th-18th centuries.; Painting, Renaissance -- Europe.; Painting, Renaissance -- Italy.; Poetry, Modern -- 15th and 16th centuries.; Poets, Italian -- 15th century.; Poets, Italian -- 16th century.; Ut pictura poesis (aesthetics); Art historians -- New Jersey -- Princeton -- 20th century.; Correspondence -- 20th century.; Lectures -- 20th century.; Photographs -- 20th century; Art history; Princeton University
- Film Slides, Notes on Tarro and Ariosto, Library Receipts, etc., undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Notes on Index Cards mostly on Torquato Tasso, along with notes on Giovanni Battista Tiepolo, L. Giardano, Guercino, Bernardo Castello, Anthony van Dyck, Poussin, and Miscellaneous Notes, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Misc. Research Notes for Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees", 1969-1970; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Research Notes and Correspondence for Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees", 1970-1977; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Research Notes for Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees", 1965-1979; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Research Bruckenthal Article, etc. for Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees", 1967-1975; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Research/Photographs B. Lutin and Rocca for Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees", 1962-1973; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Research on Individual Paintings for Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees", undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Text and Notes Drafts for Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees", 1967-1972; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- First Draft of Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees", undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Drafts and Notes for Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees", undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Drafts for Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees" and "Philadelphia Version and Variants", undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- Final Version Part III of Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees", undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
- Original Typed Copy of Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees", undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
- Photographs for Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees", Carving Research, 1942; 1 folder (Folder 13)
- Photographs for Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees" by Angelica Carues, 1956-1962; 1 folder (Folder 14)
- Photographs for Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees" by Medoro Carues, 1957-1963; 1 folder (Folder 15)
- Alternate Photographs for Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees", 1946-1964; 1 folder (Folder 16)
- Photographs for Lee's book on Ludovico Ariosto "Names on Trees", 1956-1976; 1 folder (Folder 17)
- 2 Notebooks, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Notes on Tasso Illustrations, Notes on Medieval Manuscripts, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Notes on Tasso Illustrations, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Notes on Tasso and Ariosto, undated; 2 folders (Folder 4-5)
- Notes on Tasso, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Correspondence with Erwin Panofsky, 1936-1968; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Misc. Notes, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Misc. Research Notes on Tasso, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Correspondence with individuals, 1943-1984; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Draft of renew of Friedlander's Poussin (1966), 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Letters to Lee, 1960-1973; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- 2 Photographs of Engraved Plank, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- "Francis Bacon's Essay of Beauty" by A. Philip McMahon, 1945 September; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Preliminary account of the progect "Titian iin Rome", 1950 October 26; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Postcard from Florence from Eugenio Garin, 1967 December 1; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- Misc. Reviews and Correspondences, 1952-1981; 1 folder (Folder 11)
- "The Art Bulletin", "Eye, Mind, and Hand in Michelangelo's Poetry", "Offprint from Essays in Honor of George Swarzenski", "Reviews" from Romance Philology, "El Greco's Laocoon in the National Gallery" reprinted from the Gazette des Beaux-Arts, 1949-1954; 1 folder (Folder 12)
- Estate, 1985; 1 folder (Folder 13)
- Professional Correspondence, 1930-1939; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Professional Correspondence, 1940-1949; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Professional Correspondence, 1950; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Professional Correspondence, 1951; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Professional Correspondence, 1952; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Professional Correspondence, 1953; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Professional Correspondence, 1955; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- Professional Correspondence, 1956; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Professional Correspondence, 1957; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Professional Correspondence, 1958; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- Professional Correspondence, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 11)
- Professional Correspondence, 1961; 1 folder (Folder 12)
- Professional Correspondence, 1962; 1 folder (Folder 13)
- Professional Correspondence, 1964; 1 folder (Folder 14)
- Professional Correspondence, 1967; 1 folder (Folder 15)
- Professional Correspondence, 1969; 1 folder (Folder 16)
- Professional Correspondence, 1970; 1 folder (Folder 17)
- Professional Correspondence, 1971; 1 folder (Folder 18)
- Professional Correspondence, 1973; 1 folder (Folder 19)
- Professional Correspondence, 1974; 1 folder (Folder 20)
- Professional Correspondence, 1975; 1 folder (Folder 21)
- Professional Correspondence, 1976; 1 folder (Folder 22)
- Professional Correspondence, 1977; 1 folder (Folder 23)
- Tintoretto-Origin of the Milky Way Correspondence, 1977; 1 folder (Folder 24)
- Professional Correspondence, 1978; 1 folder (Folder 25)
- Professional Correspondence, 1979; 1 folder (Folder 26)
- Professional Correspondence, 1980; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Lilly-Penn Colloquium, 1980; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Professional Correspondence, 1981; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- General Correspondence, 1982; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Professional Correspondence, 1983; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Professional Correspondence, 1984; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Letters and Memorabilia, 1949-1984; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- "French Painting in the Time of Jean de Berry" by Julian Brown, 1969; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Misc. Res. Notes, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Carbons, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- Checkbook, Bank Statements, and Deposits, 1978; 1 folder (Folder 11)
- Letters, 1976-1982; 1 folder (Folder 12)
- Letters, Memorabilia, addresses, 1980; 1 folder (Folder 13)
- Letters of recommendation, undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
- P.U. Press, 1964-1977; 1 folder (Folder 15)
- Letters-Books, 1964-1978; 1 folder (Folder 16)
- A.A.A.S. and A.P.S., 1974-1980; 1 folder (Folder 17)
- Invitation from the Art Museum of the University in Honor of Lee, undated; 1 folder (Folder 18)
- Organizations: Miscellaneous, 1962 December; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- The Academy of American Poets (empty), undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1964-1981; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- American Council of Learned Societies, 1951-1984; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- The American Philosophical Society, 1977-1984; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- The American Philosophical Society, 1984; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Archaeological Institute of America: Princeton Society, circa 1980-1981; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- Archives of American Art, 1965-1982; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- The Atheneum, 1975-1984; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- The Century Association, 1964-1984; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- College Art Association, 1944-1975; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- College Art Association: The Art Bulletin, 1976-1981; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Columbia University, 1962; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- The Cosmos Club, 1976-1980; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Federation Internationale des Societes et Instituts pour L'Etude de la Renaissance, 1960-1967; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Frick: Symposium and Museum, 1956-1966; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- Institute for Advanced Study, 1969-1984; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Institute for Fine Arts, New York University: Council of Friends, 1977-1979; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Kunsthistorisches Instint-Florence, 1955-1956; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- Lexicon Iconographicum Mythologiae Classicae (LIMC), 1977-1980; 1 folder (Folder 11)
- Mellon Center for British Art: Yale University, 1972-1976; 2 folders (Folder 12-13)
- The Nassau Club, 1979-1984; 1 folder (Folder 14)
- National Endowment for the Humanities, 1966; 1 folder (Folder 15)
- National Gallery of Art, D.C., 1966; 1 folder (Folder 16)
- Northwestern University, 1971; 1 folder (Folder 17)
- The Renaissance Society, 1962-1984; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Rhode Island School of Design, 1964; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- The Shakespeare Society of Philadelphia, 1955-1984; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Smith College, 1962; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- I Tatti, 1968-1983; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- I Tatti: C.H. Smyth Festschrift, 1955-1984; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Union Academique Internationale, 1964-1982; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- The Wistar Association, 1980-1984; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Misc., 1963-1979; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- American Academy in Rome: Misc., 1959-1970; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- American Academy in Rome: Correspondence and Misc., 1976-1984; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- American Academy in Rome: Correspondence, 1971-1976; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- American Academy in Rome: Misc., 1969-1971; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- American Academy in Rome: The Library, 1970-1971; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- American Academy in Rome: Correspondence, 1964-1968; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- American Academy in Rome: Correspondence (Rec. and Sent), 1969 January 1-February 28; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- American Academy in Rome: Correspondence (Rec. and Sent), 1969 March 1-June 30; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- American Academy in Rome: Correspondence, 1969 July 1-August 31; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- American Academy in Rome: Correspondence (Rec. and Sent), 1969 September 1-December 31; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- American Academy in Rome: Letters Sent, 1970; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Letters Received and Misc., 1970; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- American Academy in Rome: Minutes, 1968-1969; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- American Academy in Rome: Minutes, 1968-1970; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- American Academy in Rome: Financial Reports, 1965-1971; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Princeton University: Dept. of Art/Arch.: General Buisiness, 1959-1984; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Princeton University: Dept. of Art/Arch.: Advisory Council, 1976-1984; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Princeton University: Dept. of Art/Arch.: Frank Jewett Mather, 1924-1954; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Princeton University: Dept. of Art/Arch.: Graduate Students Fund, 1984; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Princeton University: Dept. of Art/Arch.: History, 1963-1983; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Princeton University: Index of Christian Art, 1963-1981; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Princeton University Art Museum, 1957-1981; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- Princeton University: Morgantina Project, 1975-1976; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Princeton University: Dept. of Art/Arch.: Building, 1956-1972; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Princeton University, 1959-1984; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Princeton University: Class of 1920, 1975-1984; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Princeton University: Firestone and Collections, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Princeton University: Firestone Library: Friends, 1980-1984; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Princeton University Press, 1976; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- The Council of the Humanities, 1954; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Lectures: Friedlander NYU Fine Arts 225/226, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Lecture Notes: Friedlander NYU Fine Arts 225/226 #1, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Lecture Notes: Friedlander NYU Fine Arts 225/226 #2, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Lectures: Friedlander NYU Fine Arts 227 + 268, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- 18th Century French Painting: Bibl., Notes, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- 18th Century French Painting: Watteau: Notes, Bibl., 1952-1966; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Lectures: Friedlander NYU Late 16th Century: Krautheimer NYU Baroque Architecture, 1941; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Lectures: C.R. Morey Medieval Art, 1923; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Lectures:"Greek Art- 12", undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Notes: Spanish Art, French 17th Century Art, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Notes: Art 12 (Smith College): Examinations (Smith College), 1940-1942; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Notes/Precepts: Medieval Art (318a) Celtic-Romanesque; Gothic; Slide Lists; Precepts (Art 303), undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Notes: Italian Baroque #1, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- Notes: Italian Baroque #2, undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Courses: Northwestern, 1932-1945; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Misc. Notes, Bibliography: Columbia, 1951-1952; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- Art 210 (Italian Renaissance Painting): Course Outlines Princeton, 1959-1962; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Art 210: Princeton: Intro Lecture, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Art 210: Princeton: Lecture and Notes: 1) Byz. and Gothic Background 2) Classic Background, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Art 210: Princeton: Lecture and Notes: 1) Cimabve and Duccio 2) Giotto 3) Sienna, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Art 210: Princeton: Lecture and Notes: 1) 14th Century, 2nd Half 2) International Style and Humanism, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Art 210: Princeton: Lecture and Notes: Pollaiuolo and Piero della Francesca, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Art 210: Princeton: Lecture and Notes: Fra Angelico, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- Art 210: Princeton: Lecture and Notes: 1) Masaccio + "Early 15th C. Realists" 2) Masaccio D. Veneziano "The First Generation of Florentine Renaissance Painters", undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Art 210: Princeton: Lecture and Notes: 1) Mantegna 2) Lippi Gozzoli, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Art 210: Princeton: Lecture and Notes: 1)Melozzo; Signorelli; Perugino 2) Raphael, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- Art 210: Princeton: Lecture and Notes: Venetian Painting (Several Lectures), undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
- Art 210: Princeton: Lecture and Notes: Correggio, Mannerism, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
- Art 303 (1957): Slide Lists, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
- Lectures and Notes: Misc., undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
- Medieval Art: Lecture/Notes, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- French Painting: Lecture/Notes, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Lectures: Poussin, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Research Notes: Poussin, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Bibliography: Poussin, Antique, 17-18th Centuries, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- "Topics for Theses, Etc." with letter from Frederick B. Deknatel, 1949; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Photograph/Slide Lists: 17-18th Century Art, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- Art Theory Course: Reading Lists, Notes, 1969; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Alberti: Notes, 1963; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Leonardo: Notes, 1963; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- Michelangelo: Notes, 1963; 1 folder (Folder 11)
- Dolce, Vasari, Lomazzo: Notes, 1964; 1 folder (Folder 12)
- Examinations, 1940-1963; 1 folder (Folder 13)
- Notes: Student Exams: L. Cook, G. Mas, M. Roskill, undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
- Student Research Papers, 1955-1973; 1 folder (Folder 15)
- Teaching Notes, Materials: Misc., 1956-1986; 1 folder (Folder 16)
- Research: Misc. Notes, 1958-1979; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Research: Misc., 1972-1974; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Research: Ancient Painting Analogies, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Research: Art and the Council of Trent, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Research: Misc. and Perseus/Andromeda, 1972-1974; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Research: Perseus and Andromeda- Photographs, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Research: "Castelvetro", 1940; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- Research: "Footnote on the Italian Baroque Iconography of Dido's Abandonment of Aeneas", undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Domenico Mona: Research, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Domenico Mona: Research "D.M. and Ferrara (Mazza, Casa di Rispaimio, (1976)", 1971-1977; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- Photographs from Mona Article (from American Philosophical Society), undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
- Photographs: Ariosto | Tasso (Negatives), undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Photos: Misc., 1955-1964; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Photos: Tapestries, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Photographs: "Mythological Subjects", undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Photographs: Verdier, Francois (1651-1730); F. Perrier, 1955-1958; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Photographs: "Duplicates and Frick Negatives", 1955-1958; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Photographs: Misc. | Unidentified, undated; 2 folders (Folder 7-8)
- Catalogues: Misc. Books, 1951-1955; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Bibliography: Misc., 1943-1953; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto II, 1936-1970; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto II Olindo and Sofronia, 1965-1973; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Tasso: Photographs: Erminia as Shepherd Canto VII, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto VII Erminia and the Shepherds, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto VII Book Illustrations Erminia and the Shepherds, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto VII Erminia Asleep, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto VII Erminia Divested, 1938-1958; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto VII Erminia comes upon the Shepherd and his sons, 1929-1977; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto VII Erminia's conversation with the Shepherd, 1942-1947; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto VII Erminia Carving Names, 1969; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto XII Baptism of Clorinda, 1924-1979; 1 folder (Folder 11)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto XII Tancred and Clorinda (Scenes other than Baptism), 1931-1953; 1 folder (Folder 12)
- Tasso: Photographs: Canto XIV Book Illustrations Godfrey's Dream, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
- Tasso: Photographs: Canto XIV Armida's Attempt to slay Rinaldo (and other scenes), 1963-1976; 1 folder (Folder 14)
- Tasso: Photographs: Canto XIV Armida Abducts Rinaldo, 1932-1976; 1 folder (Folder 15)
- Tasso: Photographs: Canto XIV Rinaldo and Armida Flower Episode, 1958-1977; 1 folder (Folder 16)
- Tasso: Photographs: Canto XV, 1931-1937; 1 folder (Folder 17)
- Tasso: Photographs: Canto XVI, 1956-1960; 1 folder (Folder 18)
- Tasso: Photographs: Canto XVI Rinaldo and Armida, 1917-1960; 1 folder (Folder 19)
- Tasso: Photographs: Canto XVI Abandonment of Rinaldo and Armida, 1957-1972; 1 folder (Folder 20)
- Tasso: Photographs: Canto XVI The Abandonment, 1951; 1 folder (Folder 21)
- Tasso: Photographs: Canto XVI Rinaldo sees his image in the shield, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Tasso: Photographs: Canto XVI Rinaldo and Armida in the Fortunate Isles, 1917-1954; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Tasso: Photographs: Canto XVI Rinaldo and Armida in the Fortunate Isles Looking Glass Scenes Only, 1934-1979; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Tasso: Photographs: Canto XVIII Rinaldo in the Enchanted Forest, 1935-1977; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto XIX Book Illustrations, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto XIX Erminia Cutting her Hair, 1938-1968; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto XIX Erminia Rushes to the Wounded Tancred, 1938-1969; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto XIX Erminia's Laments, 1968-1977; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Canto XIX Erminia Tends Tancred's Wounds, 1925-1972; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Tasso: Photographs: Canto XX Reconciliation of Rinaldo and Armida after the Latter's Attempted Suicide, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- Tasso: Photographs: Tancred and Clorinda Book Illustrations, undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
- Tasso: Research: Olindo and Sophronia- Illustrations by Canto, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
- Tasso: Photographs: Misc./Unidentified, 1919-1970; 1 folder (Folder 13)
- Tasso: Photographs: "Illustrations", undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
- Tasso: Photographs: Aminta Etc., 1936-1937; 1 folder (Folder 1)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Coypel, 1909-1982; 1 folder (Folder 2)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Guardi, Piazzetta, and Misc., 1959-1979; 1 folder (Folder 3)
- Tasso: Photographs: Laurent de la Hyra, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Angelica Kauffman, 1923-1957; 1 folder (Folder 5)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Carle van Loo, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Claude Lorrain, 1949; 1 folder (Folder 7)
- Tasso: Research Notes: Molinari, Giovanni Di (Maniera Di), undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Naples, 1937-1956; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Tasso: Photographs: "Pinelli Etc.", undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
- Tasso: Photographs/Research Notes: Poussin and Followers, 1921-1960; 1 folder (Folder 11)
- Tasso: Photographs: Tassi, Agostino Frescos, Palazzo Lancellotti, Rome, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)